It's a flower!
‫إنّها زهرة!‬
A flower?
‫زهرة؟‬
Oh, never mind. It's a person.
‫أخطأت، إنه بشري‬
What is he?
‫من هو؟‬
That old guy killed an imperial squid in one fell swoop...
‫قتل ذلك العجوز الحبّار الملكيّ العملاق بضربة!‬
Was he just fishing...
‫أكان يصطاد،‬
or was he trying to save us...?
‫أم أراد إنقاذنا؟‬
Say something already, jerk!
‫قل شيئًا أيها الوغد!‬
I-If you wanna fight, we'll fight, you bastard!
‫إ-إن كنتَ تريد القتال، فلكَ ذلك أيها الوغد!‬
We've got cannons!
‫لدينا مدافع!‬
You'd better stop what you're doing before someone dies.
‫إيّاكم واستخدامها، وإلّا... فسيلقى أحدهم حتفه‬
And just who's gonna die?
‫ومن سيلقى حتفه؟‬
Me.
‫أنا.‬
You?!
‫أنت؟!‬
You damn...
‫أيها...‬
Hey, calm down.
‫على رسلك‬
That bastard's mocking us...
‫يسخر ذلك الوغد منّا‬
Hey, gramps!
‫أيها العجوز‬
When asking someone a question,
‫عندما تسأل أحدًا،‬
don't you think it's polite to introduce yourself first?
‫أوَليس من المهذَّب أن تُعرّف بنفسك أوَّلًا؟‬
Sorry about that.
‫المعذرة‬
– My name is Crocus. – I'm Roro... noa...
‫–اسمي رورونـ‬ ‫اسمي كروكس‬
I'm the lighthouse keeper of the Twin Capes.
‫أنا حارس منارة الرَّأسين التَّوأم‬
I'm seventy-one and a Gemini.
‫عمري واحد وسبعون‬
My blood type is AB.
‫«برجي الجوزاء، وفصيلة دمي هي «أ ب‬
Let me cut him down!
‫أيمكنني قطعه؟!‬
Hey, calm down.
‫على مهلك‬
You want to know where we are?
‫أتسألون أين نحن؟‬
How dare you barge into my private resort and run your mouth at me?
‫كيف تجرأتم على السؤال بعد اقتِحامكم منتجعي الخاصّ؟‬
Where do you think we are? A rat's belly?
‫أين تظنوننا؟ في معدة جرذ؟‬
S-So we were eaten by the whale after all...
‫ا-ابتلعنا الحوت فعلًا!‬
But is this really the inside of a whale's stomach?
‫لكن، أهذا المكان داخل معدته حقًا؟‬
Wait! What's gonna happen to us?!
‫مهلًا لحظة، ما الذي سيحدث لنا؟‬
I don't wanna be digested!
‫لا أريد أن أُهضم!‬
– Cut that out already!
‫هلّا توقفتَ عن ذلك؟!‬
Haven't you kids heard of the running gag?
‫ألم تسمعوا بمزحةٍ متكرّرة؟‬
– That was a gag?!
‫أكانت مزحة؟‬
The exit is over there.
‫المخرج هناك‬
– We can get out?!
‫بوسعنا الخروج؟‬
Hold on a sec! Why is there an exit in a whale's stomach?!
‫تمهّل! أنى لمعدة الحوت مخرج؟‬
And why is the door in the sky?!
‫ولمَ الباب في السماء؟‬
Wait... Look at it carefully...
‫مهلًا، أمعني النظر‬
This sky... Those seagulls...
‫السماء والغيوم والنوارس...‬
They're all painted!
‫كلّها رسومات فحسب!‬
It's all a painting inside the whale's stomach!
‫إنّها مجرد رسومات داخل معدة الحوت!‬
Call it a doctor's whimsy.
‫يمكنكم وصفه بخيال طبيب مرِح‬
What the hell are you doing in here, you bastard?!
‫أيها الوغد! ما الذي تفعله هنا؟!‬
That's enough. Just ignore him.
‫هذا يكفي، دعوه وشأنه‬
Agreed.
‫أوافقك‬
Nami! We found the exit, so let's just get out of here.
‫لنخرج ما دمنا وجدنا مخرجًا يا نامي‬
Yeah.
‫أجل‬
What's going on?!
‫ماذا يحدث؟!‬
It's started again...
‫بدأ مجددًا‬
Look at that!
‫انظروا!‬
That's not an island!
‫إنّها ليست جزيرة،‬
It's a ship! One that's made of iron!
‫بل سفينة حديدية!‬
Oh, of course! It's because this sea is gastric acid!
‫بالطبع! فالمحيط هذا حمض مَعديّ!‬
Then our wooden ship's gonna dissolve if we stay here too long.
‫ستتهالك سفينتنا إن أطلنا البقاء إذًا‬
Hey! What's started?!
‫أنت، ما الذي بدأ؟‬
Tell us!
‫فسِّر لنا!‬
It's this whale...
‫إنّ هذا الحوت...‬
Laboon has started ramming his head into the Red Line.
‫بدأ لابون بضرب رأسه بالريد لاين‬
– What?!
‫ماذا؟‬
Come to think of it, the whale had terrible scars on his forehead.
‫بالتفكير في الأمر، لدى هذا الحوت ندوب فظيعة على جبهته‬
And the way he howled at the sky...
‫وكان يصرخ نحو السماء‬
So what?
‫ما معنى هذا؟‬
He's suffering!
‫إنه يتألَّم!‬
Oh, so that's what the geezer's doing here!
‫فهمت! هذا ما يحاول العجوز فعله‬
Most likely.
‫أُرجِّح...‬
He's probably trying to kill the whale from the inside!
‫أنَّه يحاول قتل الحوت من داخله‬
Now...
‫والآن...‬
What a vicious way to kill it!
‫يا لها من طريقة وحشيَّة!‬
Alright, mystery solved. Now let's go, quick.
‫فلنخرج بما أن اللغز حُلّ‬
We'll be digested if we stay too long.
‫سنُهضم إن بقينا‬
We have nothing to say about his whale hunting,
‫لا علاقة لنا باصطياده للحوت‬
nor do we have any reason to save the whale.
‫ولسنا ملزمين بإنقاذ الحوت‬
Let's get out of here.
‫لنغادر فحسب‬
Dammit! With the waves surging like this,
‫سُحقًا! بتقدّم الأمواج هكذا،‬
I don't know if we can even reach the doors!
‫لا أدري إن كنّا نستطيع بلوغ البوّابة حتى!‬
We're gonna have to paddle! Grab the oars!
‫لا خيار أمامنا سوى التجديف، جهّزوا المجاديف!‬
Let's speed it up! I'm worried about Luffy.
‫لنغادر بسرعة، وأنا قلقةٌ على لوفي‬
He's outside!
‫إنّه في الخارج‬
I saw him fly out of the mouth!
‫رأيته يحلّق خارج فمه‬
The old man dove in!
‫غاص العجوز!‬
Huh?
‫ماذا؟‬
What's he doing? He's gonna be dissolved.
‫ما الذي ينوي يفعله؟ سيُهضم‬
What?! What's going on?! Huh? Why?!
‫ماذا؟ ما الذي يحدث؟ لماذا؟‬
Dizzy... Dizzy...
‫دائخ، دائخ‬
I'm getting dizzy!
‫أشعر بالدوخة!‬
What now?
‫ماذا الآن؟‬
Is this the sea? A river? A canal?
‫أهذا بحر؟ نهر؟ قناة؟‬
Okay. We've infiltrated this far successfully.
‫حسنٌ، نجحنا في التسلل إلى هنا‬
Listen, Miss Wednesday.
‫اسمعي يا آنسة وينزداي،‬
The stomach is right behind these doors,
‫سنجد خلف هذه البوابة المعدة،‬
and that geezer is most likely there too.
‫وسيكون العجوز هناك‬
We must eliminate him.
‫علينا التخلّص منه‬
Our goal is the whale.
‫هدفنا هو الحوت‬
That's right, Mr. 9.
‫أجل يا سيّد 9‬
This whale will be precious, sweet honey to our town.
‫هذا الحوت بمثابة عسل حلو غالٍ لبلدتنا‬
Hey! The geezer came back up!
‫مهلًا، خرج العجوز‬
Forget about him.
‫انسَ أمره‬
More importantly, how are we gonna open those doors?
‫الأهمّ الآن، كيف نفتح هذه البّوابة؟‬
Okay, Miss Wednesday,
‫أجاهزةٌ يا آنسة وينزداي؟‬
we'll open them on "Three, two, one, baby!"
‫«!سنفتح البوّابة بعد العدّ، «ثلاثة، اثنان، واحد، عزيزتي‬
Be on your guard.
‫لا ترخي دفاعاتك‬
Roger, Mr. 9. I'm ready when you are.
‫عُلم يا سيّد 9، أنا جاهزة‬
I can't stop!
‫لا يمكنني التوقف!‬
What is this voice, Mr. 9?
‫ما هذا الصوت يا سيّد 9؟‬
I don't know, Miss Wednesday.
‫لا أدري يا آنسة وينزداي‬
Not them again...!
‫إنهم...‬
This is bad, Miss Wednesday!
‫هذا سيّئ يا آنسة وينزداي!‬
There's a sea of gastric acid below us!
‫محيطٌ من الحمض المَعديّ تحتنا!‬
Luffy?
‫لوفي؟‬
Hey! So everyone's okay?
‫مهلًا، الجميع بخير إذًا؟‬
Anyway... help me!
‫على أي حال، أنقذوني!‬
Two more weirdos came down with Luffy...
‫إلى جانب لوفي، هناك شخصان غريبان...‬
Hey! That old man disappeared!
‫اختفى ذلك العجوز!‬
Forget him. We gotta save Luffy!
‫دعكِ منه، علينا إنقاذ لوفي‬
Stop it, Laboon.
‫توقف يا لابون‬
Don't hurt yourself any more.
‫لا تؤذِ نفسك أكثر‬
There isn't much sedative left...
‫لم يبقَ إلا قليلًا من المُخدِّر،‬
I'll have to make some more.
‫عليّ تحضير المزيد‬
That wall divides the world's oceans.
‫ذلك الجدار يفصل بين محيطات العالم‬
It won't break, even if you hit it until you die, Laboon.
‫حتى لو واصلت ضربه حتى تموت، فلن يتحطّم يا لابون‬
It's calmed down!
‫هدأ!‬
The whale is quiet now.
‫قد هدأ الحوت الآن‬
Seems like it.
‫يبدو ذلك‬
Now...
‫والآن...‬
We ended up saving you guys too, but who are you?
‫آل بنا الأمر إلى إنقاذكم، من أنتم؟‬
Mr. 9, these people are pirates.
‫إنهم قراصنة يا سيّد 9‬
I-I know, Miss Wednesday.
‫أ-أعلم يا آنسة وينزداي‬
B-But if we explain it to them, they should understand... perhaps...
‫لـ-لكن إن تحدّثنا معهم، سيدركون على الأرجح...‬
You thugs are still at it?
‫أما زلتم هنا أيها الأوغاد؟‬
How many times do I need to tell you?!
‫كم مرة عليّ أن أكرّر كلامي؟!‬
You'll never lay a finger on Laboon as long as I live!
‫لن أسمح لكم بلمس لابون ما دمتُ حيًّا أُرزق!‬
He's back.
‫عاد.‬
Who's that old guy?
‫من ذلك العجوز؟‬
No matter what you say, we can't just leave.
‫لن نرحل وإن قلتَ ذلك‬
Our mission is to take down this whale.
‫مهمتنا هي الإطاحة بالحوت‬
You won't interfere with our whale hunting this time!
‫لن نسمح لك بالتدخل في عملية صيدنا للحوت هذه المرّة!‬
We'll blast a hole in his stomach!
‫سنصنع فتحة تهوية في معدته‬
Let's go, baby!
‫هيّا يا عزيزتي!‬
Roger!
‫عُلم‬
Those bastards!
‫وغدان!‬
The old guy jumped right into the shots!
‫قفز العجوز مباشرةً نحو الطلقات!‬
Was he... protecting the whale?!
‫أيُعقل أنه... حمى الحوت؟‬
Stop this futile resistance!
‫كفاكَ مقاومةً عقيمة!‬
Protect this whale all you want!
‫احمِ هذا الحوت كما تشاء،‬
But this whale will become food for our town!
‫لكنّه سيصبح طعامًا لبلدتنا!‬
What's going on?
‫ما الذي يحدث؟‬
Luffy...?
‫لوفي؟‬
They just...
‫شعرتُ...‬
had it coming.
‫وكأنّ عليّ ضربهما‬
I thank you for saving me... but why?
‫أشكرك على إنقاذي، ولكن لماذا؟‬
I wasn't trying to save you.
‫لم أقصد إنقاذك‬
I just didn't like them.
‫لم يروقا لي فحسب‬
Hey, Luffy! What're you doing?
‫مهلًا يا لوفي، ماذا تفعل؟‬ ‫أخبرني، من هذين؟‬
Stop it!
‫توقف!‬
Hey! Hey, Luffy! Stop it!
‫يا لوفي، توقف!‬ ‫إنّهما وغدان من بلدة مجاورة،‬
What are you trying to do?
‫ما الذي تنوي فعله؟‬
It belongs to someone else.
‫إنها ملكٌ لغيرك!‬
If they capture Laboon,
‫إن تمكّنا من الإمساك بلابون،‬
they'd be able to feed their town for at least two to three years.
‫فبإمكانه إطعام سكان بلدتهم لسنتين أو ثلاث على الأقل‬
Laboon?
‫لابون؟‬
That's the name of this whale.
‫إنّه اسم هذا الحوت‬
He's an island whale, a species that only lives in the West Blue.
‫يُعرف بأنه حوت جزيرة، ولا يعيش إلا في الأزرق الغربي‬
They're the biggest whales in the world.
‫إنّه الحوت الأكبر في العالم‬
I won't let them use him as food.
‫لن أسمح لهما بالحصول عليه لأكله!‬
There's a reason he keeps hitting himself against the Red Line
‫ثمّة سبب يدفعه لمواصلة ضرب رأسه بالريد لاين،‬
and howling toward Reverse Mountain.
‫والصراخ نحو الجبل المعكوس‬
A reason?
‫سبب؟‬
Yes.
‫نعم‬
He's a whale with a human heart.
‫إنّه حوت بقلب بشر‬
And he's been devotedly waiting for a certain pirate crew...
‫ما زال ينتظر طاقم قراصنة معيّن بأيّما إخلاص‬
for fifty long years...
‫منذ خمسين عامًا!‬
This... is Laboon's story...
‫سأخبركم... بقصّة لابون...‬
One day, while I was on duty as the lighthouse keeper,
‫في أحد الأيامِ وبينما كنت أعمل كحارس للمنارة كعادتي،‬
some good-natured pirates came down Reverse Mountain
‫نزل بعض القراصنة الطيبين من الجبل المعكوس‬
to enter the Grand Line.
‫ليدخلوا إلى الغراند لاين‬
And a small whale came down too, seemingly following them.
‫وكان معهم حوت صغير تبعهم‬
That was Laboon.
‫وذلك كان لابون‬
As I said before, the island whale is the largest whale species,
‫كما أخبرتكم، حيتان الجزيرة تُعدّ من أكبر الحيتان في العالم‬
and only lives in the West Blue.
‫وتعيش في الأزرق الغربيّ فقط‬
The pirates had been traveling with Laboon the entire time,
‫أبحر القراصنة برفقة لابون فترة طويلة،‬
but they left him behind because of how dangerous the Grand Line is.
‫لكنّهم تركوه في الأزرق الغربيّ بما أنّ الغراند لاين خطير جدًّا‬
But Laboon followed without them noticing.
‫لكن لابون تبعهم دون أن يلاحظوا‬
Since their ship had broken down, they stayed here for several months.
‫وبما أنّ سفينتهم تحطّمت، بقوا هنا لعدّة أشهر‬
We became close friends in that time.
‫لذلك أصبحنا أصدقاء مقرّبين آن ذاك‬
Because of that, on the day of their departure...
‫وبسبب ذلك، أخبروني وقت رحيلهم...‬
I need to ask you a favor, my friend.
‫لدينا ما نطلبه منك بما أنّنا نثق بك‬
Can you take care of Laboon for two or three years?
‫أيمكنك الاعتناء به لعامين أو ثلاثة؟‬
We'll return after sailing around the world.
‫سنعود حالما ننتهي من الإبحار حول العالم‬
Listen up, Laboon.
‫اسمع يا لابون‬
We're going to enter the Grand Line and circumnavigate the world.
‫سنذهب إلى الغراند لاين وسنبحر حول العالم‬
But please wait for us here.
‫لكن انتظرنا هنا رجاءً‬
We're going to a dangerous place.
‫إنّه مكان خطير‬
Too dangerous for you to come along.
‫لا يمكننا اصطحابك معنا‬
Don't worry. Three years will go by in a flash.
‫لا تقلق، ستمرّ الأعوام الثلاثة بلمح البصر‬
Don't forget...
‫ولا تنسَ...‬
We'll always be family, no matter how far apart we are.
‫أننا رفاقٌ وإن فرَّقتنَا المسافات‬
Well then, we're setting off.
‫حسنٌ، سننطلق!‬
Guys! We're setting sail!
‫يا رفاق، لنبحر‬
Hoist the anchor!
‫ارفعوا المرساة!‬
– Yeah!
‫حسنًا!‬
Laboon!
‫يا لابون!‬
Wait for us, Laboon!
‫انتظرنا يا لابون!‬
We promise to return!
‫أعدّك أننا سنعود!‬
Mark my words!
‫لا تنسَ ذلك!‬
But that was fifty long years ago...
‫مرَّ على ذلك خمسونَ عامًا‬
Fifty years?
‫خمسون عامًا؟‬
Laboon's been waiting for those guys for fifty whole years?
‫بقي لابون في انتظارهم لخمسين عام؟‬
Is that why he continues to howl and ram into the rocks?
‫ألهذا السّبب يواصل الصراخ والاصطدام بالصخور؟‬
Correct.
‫أجل.‬
This is an amazing canal.
‫يا لها من قناة‬
I'm surprised that he's alive with a hole like this in him.
‫أدهشني أنه ما زال حيًّا رغم وجود ثقب ضخم في جسده‬
Was this also your old "whimsy"?
‫أهذا من صنيع عقلك المرِح أيضًا؟‬
A "doctor's whimsy."
‫«عقل «طبيب مرح‬
Doctor?
‫طبيب؟‬
I may not look it, but yes, I'm a doctor.
‫قد لا يبدو ذلك عليّ، لكنّني طبيب‬
I used to run a clinic on the cape many years ago.
‫كانت لديّ عيادة على الرأس قبل مدّة‬
I was also a ship's doctor for a few years.
‫وكنتُ أيضًا طبيب سفينة لبضعة سنوات‬
Really?
‫حقًّا؟‬
You should be one for our ship!
‫لمَ لا تصبح طبيب سفينتنا إذًا؟‬
Don't be ridiculous.
‫كفاكَ سخافةً‬
I no longer have the energy to keep up with you reckless youngsters.
‫ما عادت لدي طاقة كافية لأفعل أمور متهوّرة مثلكم‬
A doctor, huh? That explains why the whale's insides are like this...
‫طبيب؟ هذا يفسّر مظهر أحشاء الحوت‬
So this is from the treatment?
‫إنّها من أجل العلاج إذًا‬
That's right.
‫ذلك صحيح‬
It's impossible to treat a whale this big from the outside.
‫حوت بهذا الحجم يستحيل علاجه من الخارج‬
I'm opening the doors.
‫سأفتح البوّابة‬
There it is!
‫ها هي...‬
The real sky!
‫السماء الحقيقيّة!‬
Miss Wednesday, what are you...
‫آنسة وينزداي، ما الذي...‬
A whole fifty years, huh?
‫ولكن لخمسين عام...؟‬
Those pirates sure are making him wait...
‫جعلوه أولئك القراصنة ينتظر طويلًا‬
Idiot.
‫أحمق!‬
This is the Grand Line.
‫هذا الغراند لاين‬
They're dead.
‫قد ماتوا‬
They won't come back no matter how long he waits.
‫لن يعودوا مهما طال انتظاره‬
Yeah, because it was basically uncharted fifty years ago,
‫صحيح، كان الغراند لاين قبل خمسين عامًا بحرًا مجهولًا‬
the Grand Line was more terrible and chaotic than it is now.
‫وقد كان أكثر فظاعة وفوضويّة من الآن‬
Why are you being so cynical?!
‫لمَ أنتم متشائمون هكذا؟‬
You don't know that for sure!
‫لا يمكنكم الجزم بذلك!‬
They could still come back!
‫قد يعودون!‬
It's such a touching story!
‫إنها قصّة مؤثرة للغاية،‬
A whale believing in his friends' promise for fifty long years...
‫حوتٌ ما زال يُؤمن بوعدِ رفاقه...‬
Isn't it, pops?!
‫أصحيح أيها العجوز؟‬
Yeah...
‫أجل...‬
But unfortunately, reality is cruel.
‫ولكن للأسف، الواقع قاسٍ‬
I heard from a reliable source...
‫تأكّدتُ من مصدرٍ ثقة...‬
No way...
‫لا يُعقل...‬
You're telling me they left him behind?!
‫أتعني أنهم تخلّوا عنه؟!‬
Fled the Grand Line...
‫هربوا من الغراند لاين...‬
So they crossed the Calm Belt and lived?
‫أيعني هذا أنهم اجتازوا الحزام الهادئ أحياء؟‬
Whether they're alive or not,
‫سواء كانوا أحياء أم لا،‬
I doubt they'll ever return.
‫فأنا أشكّ بعودتهم‬
Seasons. Weather. Current. Wind direction.
‫المواسم والجوّ والتيار واتجاه الرياح‬
They're all random here.
‫كلّها عشوائيّة هنا‬
Common sense is useless in the Grand Line.
‫لا جدوى للمنطق السّائد في هذا البحر‬
Weak hearts soon succumb to fear on the Grand Line.
‫يستولي رعب الغراند لاين على القلوب الضعيفة في لحظة‬
So the weak of heart chose to run away,
‫أي أنّهم هربوا من هذا البحر لضعف قلوبهم،‬
caring more about their lives than the promise they made...
‫وتخلّوا عن وعدهم لينجوا بحياتهم‬
They abandoned the whale?!
‫تخلّوا عن الحوت؟!‬
While he's been waiting here for fifty years?!
‫وهو الذي لا زال ينتظرهم لخمسين عامًا؟!‬
That's too cruel!
‫هذا قاسٍ!‬
If you know that, why haven't you told him?
‫ما دمت تعرف الحقيقة، فلمَ لم تخبره؟‬
He can understand human speech, right?
‫بإمكان الحيتان فهم كلام البشر، أليس كذلك؟‬
I did tell him.
‫أخبرتُه سلفًا‬
I tried to tell him the whole story.
‫حاولت إخباره كلّ شيء‬
Laboon! Listen up!
‫اسمع يا لابون!‬
I heard that those pirates have fled the Grand Line.
‫سمعتُ أنهم غادروا الغراند لاين‬
I know that you were friends,
‫كنتم رفاقَ فعلًا،‬
and that the promise they made with you was certainly genuine...
‫والوعد الذي قطعوه لك كان صادقًا أيضًا‬
But I'm afraid...
‫ولكنّي أخشى...‬
they will never return...
‫أنهم لن يعودوا مجددًا...‬
Laboon! Listen to me!
‫استمع إليّ يا لابون...‬
They will never–
‫إنّهم لن...‬
I understand that you don't want to believe it...
‫أدرك أنّك لا تود تصديق هذا،‬
but you must accept it somehow!
‫لكن عليك تقبل الحقيقة!‬
Laboon!
‫لابون!‬
It was on that day that he began howling at Reverse Mountain
‫ومذّاك الحين، بدأ لابون بالصراخ على الجبل المعكوس‬
and ramming his body against the Red Line...
‫ويضرب رأسه بالريد لاين،‬
It's as if he's insisting
‫وكأنه مُصرٌّ على عودتهم‬
they will come down the other side of that wall any day now...
‫من الجانب الآخر في أي لحظة‬
What a whale...
‫يا له من حوت...‬
Even though there's no point in waiting...
‫رغم أن لا جدوى من الانتظار‬
He refuses to believe me because if I'm right, there would be no reason to wait.
‫رفض تصديقي لأنّه إن صَدّقني سيعني ذلك أن لا جدوى من الانتظار‬
He's afraid of that more than anything.
‫تلك الحقيقة هي أكثر ما يخشاه‬
His home is in the West Blue...
‫موطنه هو الأزرق الغربيّ‬
but there's no way to return from here.
‫لكنّ العودةَ إليه باتت مُحالة‬
Those pirates were not only his friends, but his hope for going home.
‫لم يكن أولئك القراصنة رفاقه فحسب بل وأمله في العودة لموطنه أيضًا‬
While I do feel bad for the whale,
‫رغم أنني أشعر بالأسى تجاهه،‬
they betrayed you, too, right?
‫لكنك تعرّضت للخيانة أيضًا، أليس كذلك؟‬
Haven't you taken care of him long enough?
‫ألم تبذل كل ما في وسعك من أجله؟‬
Look at the scars on his forehead!
‫انظر للنّدوب على جبهته!‬
If he continues to ram his head like that, he'll surely die.
‫إن واصل ضرب رأسه بشدّة هكذا، سيموت بلا شكّ‬
It's an odd relationship, but I've been with him for fifty years.
‫إنها علاقة غريبة، لكنّي رافقته طوالَ خمسينَ عامًا‬
I can't just stand by and watch him die.
‫لن أقف مكتوف اليدين وأراه يموت‬
What's that idiot doing now?
‫ما الذي يفعله هذا الغبيّ؟‬
We only looked away for a second...
‫نشيح بنظرنا للحظة وهذا ما يحدث...‬
Does he think he's a mountain climber?
‫أيحسب نفسه متسلّق جبال؟‬
Gum-Gum...
‫فاكهة المطاط‬ ‫غومو غومو نو‬
Bouquet!
‫تنسيق الزهور‬ ‫إيكيبانا‬
Isn't that a mast?
‫أليست تلك صارية؟‬
Yep. The one from our ship.
‫نعم، صارية سفينتنا‬
The main mast, yes.
‫الصارية الرئيسية.‬
Hey! Don't break the ship!
‫مهلًا! لا تحطّم السّفينة!‬
– What the hell are you doing?!
‫ما الذي تفعله؟!‬
Wha...?! Hey, kid!
‫ما... أيها الفتى!‬
Don't worry! He can't die from being crushed!
‫لا تقلق، لن يموت حتى إن سُحق‬
Dummy!
‫أحمق!‬
What's he thinking?
‫ما الذي يفكّر فيه؟‬
Luffy! What the hell are you trying to do?!
‫ما الذي تفعله يا لوفي؟‬
It's a draw!
‫إنّه تعادل!‬
I'm pretty strong, huh?
‫أنا قويّ، صحيح؟‬
Our fight isn't over yet!
‫لم ينتهِ قتالنا بعد!‬
We'll have to settle things later!
‫لذا علينا أن نتقاتل مجددًا‬
Your friends might be dead, but I'll always be your rival!
‫مات رفاقك، ولكني غريمك الأبديّ الآن‬
One day, we definitely gotta settle this and see who's stronger.
‫سنتقاتل ثانيةً حتمًا لنعرف من الأقوى بيننا‬
After we go around the Grand Line, we'll come back to see you again.
‫بعد أن نقطع الغراند لاين سنأتي لنراك ثانيةً‬
When I come back, we'll finish our fight!
‫سنكمل قتالنا حينما أعود!‬
Perfect.
‫ممتاز!‬
This symbol means we promise to fight again.
‫هذه علامة وعدنا بالقتال ثانيةً‬
So don't ram into stuff or you'll erase it before we get back. Got it?!
‫وإلى أن نعود ثانيةً، إيّاك أن تضرب رأسك فتُزال العلامة، مفهوم؟‬
Alright!
‫حسنًا!‬
Where'd those guys go?
‫أين ذينك الاثنان؟‬
"Those guys"?
‫ذينك الاثنان؟‬
Oh, you mean those two weirdos?
‫أتقصد ذينك الغريبَين؟‬
Maybe they ran away?
‫ربّما هربا؟‬
We never did find out what their deal was, huh...
‫أتساءل من كانا‬
Whatever do we do now, Miss Wednesday?
‫ما العمل الآن يا آنسة وينزداي؟‬
At the very least, we'll need to go back and report to the boss...
‫على أيّ حال، علينا العودة لتقديم تقريرنا للزّعيم‬
We were supposed to finish this mission long ago.
‫تجاوزنا الوقت المحدد لإنهاء مهمتنا منذ مدّة‬
You're right. It would be bad if they begin to suspect us of treachery.
‫صدقتِ، إن راودهم الشك فينا فستكون مصيبة!‬
Indeed.
‫أجل‬
Since we lost our weapons, we have to return to base and start over.
‫وبما أنّنا فقدنا أسلحتنا، علينا العودة لقاعدتنا والبدء من جديد‬
If we must. Well then, let us... begin... Huh?
‫ما باليد حيلة... علينا... البدء...‬
Um...? Where is...? What?!
‫ما... ماذا؟!‬
What's the matter?
‫ما الخطب؟‬
It's gone...
‫اختفت‬
What?
‫ماذا؟‬
What's this?
‫ما هذه؟‬
You dropped the log pose?!
‫أسقطتَ البوصلة المسجّلة؟‬
I apologize, Miss Wednesday!
‫أعتذر يا آنسة وينزداي!‬
And we need it to return home...
‫لن نستطيع العودة لبلدتنا من دونها‬
As it stands–
‫على هذه الحالة...‬
I-Is that...?!
‫أ-أيُعقل أنّهما...‬
It's...
‫إنّهما...‬
O-Oh no...
‫مـ-مستحيل...‬
...the Unluckies!
‫إنّهما المشؤومان!‬
Darn! Are we too late?!
‫كلّا! أفات الأوان؟‬
Mr. 13!
‫سيّد 13!‬
Miss Friday!
‫آنسة فرايداي!‬
Please wait! We can explain!
‫مهلًا، رجاءً! دعونا نبرّر موقفنا!‬
We'll report to the boss immediately!
‫سنرسل تقريرنا للزعيم حالًا!‬
Now then! I finally get to chart out our Grand Line journey.
‫ها قد حان الوقت لأخطّط لرحلتنا في الغراند لاين‬
Alright! I can finally cook up the elephant bluefin tuna!
‫آن أوان طهي سمكة التونة ذو الزعانف الزرقاء الهائلة!‬
Damn...!
‫سُحقًا!‬
What was Luffy thinking, wrecking our ship! Really...
‫كيف تجرّأ لوفي على تحطيم سفينتنا؟ يا إلهي...‬
Hey, Zoro!
‫يا زورو!‬
Give me a hand! I'm not exactly a shipwright!
‫هيّا ساعدني أنا لستُ نجّار سُفنٍ‬
What's with the screaming?
‫لِمَ الصراخ؟‬
Is all well, Nami?!
‫ما الخطب يا نامي-سان؟‬
If you're hungry, I have our meal right here!
‫إن كنتِ جائعة، فالطعام جاهز‬
Time to eat?
‫الطعام جاهز؟‬
Th-The compass is broken!
‫تـ-تعطَّلت البوصلة!‬
It's not pointing anywhere!
‫إنّها لا تشير لأيّ اتّجاه!‬
Hey, you're right.
‫إنّكِ محقّة‬
It keeps spinning.
‫إنّها تدور وتدور‬
Whoa! Neat!
‫كم هذا ممتع!‬
Looks like you guys came here unprepared.
‫يبدو أنّكم أتيتم إلى هنا دونَ أيِّ معرفةٍ مسبقة‬
For heaven's sake! Did you come here to die?
‫يا إلهي، هل أتيتم لتلقوا حتفكم؟‬
What?
‫ماذا؟‬
Food?
‫طعام؟‬
You'll be eating hay.
‫اصمت وكُل‬
I thought I told you...
‫أظنّني أخبرتكم‬
Common sense is useless in this sea.
‫لا جدوى للمنطق السّائد في هذا البحر‬
It's not that the compass is broken...
‫المشكلة ليست أنّ بوصلتك معطّلة‬
Then, is it the magnetic fields?
‫أهي المجالات المغناطيسيّة؟‬
Correct.
‫أجل‬
The islands in the Grand Line are rich in magnetic minerals.
‫تحتوي جزر الغراند لاين على عديدٍ من المعادن المغناطيسيّة‬
They cause abnormalities throughout the Grand Line.
‫وبسبب ذلك، تتسبّب بالكثير من التشوّهات عبر الغراند لاين‬
Furthermore, the current and wind patterns are never consistent.
‫إضافةً إلى ذلك، فإنّ التيار والرياح ليسا مستقرّين‬
As a navigator, you should know how terrifying that is.
‫إن كنتِ ملّاحةً فلا بدّ أنّكِ تدركين مدى خطورة ذلك‬
We'll have no hope of survival without a way to know our direction...
‫فعلًا، لن نملك أملًا بالنجاةِ دونَ وسيلةٍ تُعيننا على معرفة الاتجاه‬
Yummy!
‫لذيذة!‬
I-I didn't know! Oh, well...
‫لـ-لم أكن أعلم، المعذرة...‬
Hey! That's really bad! Are we gonna be okay?!
‫مهلًا! هذا سيّئ، هل سنكون بخير؟‬
This isn't bad. It's yummy!
‫لا بأس بها، إنها لذيذة!‬
Can you guys be quiet for one second?!
‫لمَ لا تلتزما الصمت؟!‬
The nose of the elephant bluefin tuna tastes good!
‫أنف سمكة التونة ذو الزعانف الزرقاء لذيذ!‬
You need a log pose to travel around the Grand Line.
‫ستحتاجون لبوصلة مسجّلة للإبحار في الغراند لاين‬
Log pose? I've never heard of it.
‫بوصلة مسجّلة؟ لم أسمع قبلًا‬
It's a special compass that can record magnetism.
‫إنّها بوصلة خاصّة بإمكانها تسجيل المجال المغناطيسيّ‬
Like a weird-looking compass?
‫أهي بوصلة غريبة الشكل؟‬
Yes, its shape is quite unusual.
‫نعم، شكلها غير عاديّ‬
Something like this?
‫أتشبه هذه؟‬
Yeah, that's the one.
‫نعم، هذه هي‬
It's impossible to navigate the Grand Line without a log pose.
‫من دون البوصلة المسجّلة، يستحيل الإبحار في الغراند لاين‬
I see.
‫فهمت‬
But hold on a second...
‫لكن مهلًا لحظة...‬
Luffy?
‫لوفي...‬
How come you have one?!
‫كيف تملك واحدة؟!‬
Those two weirdos dropped it on the ship.
‫إنّه غرض أسقطه ذينك الغريبان على السّفينة‬
They did?
‫سقطت منهما؟‬
Why'd you hit me?
‫لمَ ضربتِني؟‬
It felt right.
‫رغبتُ في ذلك‬
Fair enough.
‫رغبتِ إذًا؟‬
So this is a log pose.
‫هذه البوصلة المسجّلة إذًا‬
There's no dial face.
‫ليس لديها واجهة‬
The magnetic fields of islands in the Grand Line follow a certain rule:
‫معروفٌ أنَّ مجالات الجزر المغناطيسيّة في الغراند لاين تتّبع نظامًا معيّنًا‬
By recording the magnetism of two islands pulling against each other,
‫فعن طريق تسجيل مجالَيْ جزيرتين تسحب كلّ واحدة منهما من جهة،‬
you can find the route to the next island.
‫يصبح بالإمكان تحديد مسار الجزيرة التالية‬
Since you can't even figure out your location in this sea,
‫وبما أنّه لا يمكنك تحديد موقعك في البحر،‬
the magnetic record of the log pose is the only thing you can depend on.
‫فسجلّ المجال المغناطيسيّ للبوصلة المسجّلة هو المرجع الموثوق‬
To begin, you must pick one of Reverse Mountain's seven magnetic fields.
‫في البداية، عليك اختيار أحد المجالات المغناطيسيّة السبعة الّتي بالجبل المعكوس‬
But no matter which route you take,
‫لكن مهما كان المسار المختار،‬
the magnetic pulls will eventually push you onto one route.
‫فإنّ جميع المجالات المغناطيسية ستقودك إلى طريقٍ واحد في النهاية‬
And the name of the island at the end of the voyage is...
‫واسم الجزيرة التي تقع في نهاية الطريق هو...‬
Laugh Tale.
‫لافتيل‬
It's the last island in the Grand Line.
‫إنّها آخر جزيرة في الغراند لاين‬
The only one in history to confirm its existence is the King of the Pirates.
‫لم يُثبت وجودها عبر التاريخ سوى ملك القراصنة وطاقمه‬
It's a legendary island.
‫إنّها جزيرة أسطوريّة‬
Laugh Tale...
‫لافتيل...‬
So is that where the One Piece is?!
‫أتُرى يقبع الون بيس هناك؟‬
Who knows. That's the most prominent theory,
‫من يدري؟ هذه هي أشهر النظريات،‬
but no one else has been able to get there.
‫فلم يستطع أحدٌ غيرهم بلوغها‬
Then...
‫إذًا...‬
we'll be the first to prove it.
‫سنكون أول من يدري عندما نصل!‬
Alright, I'm done! You guys wanna get going?
‫شبعتُ، هل ننطلق؟‬
You ate the whole thing?!
‫أكلتَ كلّ هذا وحدك؟!‬
A log pose, huh? We'd better take good care of this.
‫بوصلة مسجّلة؟ علينا الاعتناء بها جيدًّا‬
This is the key to the rest of our journey.
‫فهي مفتاح نجاح رحلتنا‬
You damn rubber man!
‫أيها المطاطي اللعين!‬
I made Nami such a delicious meal and she...
‫أردتُ لنامي-سان أن تأكل مزيدًا... أن تأكل نامي-سان مزيدًا...‬
she didn't even have a bite!
‫أردتها أن تستمتع بالطعام!‬
What was that for?
‫ما بالك؟‬
Take that, you damn rubber man.
‫تستحقّ ذلك أيها المطاطي اللعين‬
Sanji...
‫سانجي-كن...‬
Yes, Nami!
‫نعم يا نامي-سان!‬
You two should go cool your heads off!
‫اذهبا وهدآ أعصابكما!‬
Hey, hold on a sec...
‫مهلًا، انتظري لحظة‬
Wasn't that thing super-duper important?!
‫ألم تكن غرضًا بالغَ الأهميَّة؟!‬
Our precious log pose...
‫بوصلتنا المسجلّة الثمينة...‬
Don't panic. You can have mine.
‫لا تهلعي، سأعطيك بوصلتي‬
Think of it as thanks for helping Laboon.
‫كعربون شكر عمَّا فعلتموه مع لابون‬
Man... I thought I was a goner. Huh?
‫ظننتُني سأهلك‬
Here, take my hand, dear lady.
‫حسنٌ، أمسكي بيدي يا عزيزتي‬
Oh, thank you.
‫حسنًا، شكرًا لك‬
Nice day, isn't it?
‫جو اليوم جميل، صحيح؟‬
Hey!
‫مهلًا!‬
We must ask you a favor.
‫أرجو منكم طلبًا‬
Whisky Peak?
‫ويسكي بيك؟‬
That's a weird name.
‫إنّه اسم غريب‬
What's that?
‫ما هي؟‬
That's where we live... um, sir.
‫إنّها البلدة التي نعيش فيها... المعذرة‬
What happened to your ship?
‫ما الذي حلّ بسفينتكما؟‬
I'm afraid it was destroyed.
‫تحطّمت‬
That's a pretty big favor for someone who just tried to kill the whale, Mr. 9.
‫أتطلب معروفًا يا سيّد 9 مع أنك كنتَ تحاول قتل الحوت؟‬
So who are you guys, anyway?
‫ما حقيقتكما؟‬
I'm a king.
‫أنا ملك.‬
Liar.
‫كاذب‬
We can't say!
‫لا يمكننا إخباركم!‬
We just want to go back home.
‫لكنّنا نريد العودة للبلدة‬
We don't like being secretive either, but...
‫لا نريد أن نكون كتومين أيضًا، لكن...‬
...our company motto is "Mystery."
‫«مبدأ منظمتنا هو «الغموض‬
We simply can't tell you anything about us.
‫فليس بوسعنا إخباركم بأيّ شيء عنّا‬
Trusting your good character, we beg of you!
‫رأينا فيكم ما يدعو للثقة، نتوسّل إليكم‬
I assure you, we will return the favor.
‫سنردّ الجميل حتمًا‬
Don't do it.
‫إيّاكم‬
No matter what they say, they're dishonest people.
‫إنهما مخادعان مهما كان ما يتفوّهان به‬
By the way, we broke the log pose. Do you still want a ride?
‫بالمناسبة، كسرنا البوصلة المسجّلة، أما زلتم تودون المجيء معنا؟‬
What?! You broke it?! That was mine, you know!
‫ماذا؟ كسرتموها؟ إنها بوصلتي!‬
You dare act smug while we're being humble?! You're all stuck here as well!
‫تستغلّين تصرّفنا بتواضع للتعالي علينا؟ إنكم عالقون أيضًا!‬
Oh, I forgot to mention...
‫نسيتُ ذكر هذا...‬
We do have a spare, courtesy of Mr. Crocus.
‫لدينا واحدة أعطانا إيّاها كروكس-سان‬
We beg you people of such character...
‫نتوسّل إليكم يا أهل الثقة‬
Dammit! This minx is toying with us!
‫سُحقًا! خدعتنا تلك الحقيرة!‬
Sure, you can ride with us.
‫لا بأس بالمجيء معنا‬
Whisky Peak, right?
‫هل قلتُما ويسكي بيك؟‬
Let's go there.
‫لنذهب إليها‬
Hey, are you sure we wanna go out of our way to take these shady guys?
‫مهلًا، أأنت جاد؟ سنُجهد أنفسنا من أجل هذين المشبوهين؟‬
What's the problem?
‫ما المشكلة؟‬
Don't sweat the small stuff.
‫لا تشغل بالك بصغائر الأمور‬
Once you choose your route here, you won't be able to change it.
‫لن تستطيعوا تغيير مساركم بعد أن تختاروه‬
If we don't like it, we'll just go around again.
‫إن لم يعجبنا، سنعود من البداية فحسب‬
Is that so...?
‫هكذا إذًا...‬
So, should we get going?
‫حسنٌ، هل ننطلق؟‬
Since I've made my promise with the whale, let's sail out.
‫قطعتُ وعدًا لهذا الحوت، لنستعدّ للإبحار‬
Who in the world are you?
‫لكن من تكون أنت؟‬
Me?
‫أنا؟‬
I'm...
‫أنا...‬
the man who's gonna be King of the Pirates!
‫الرجل الذي سيصبح ملك القراصنة!‬
What a foolish pirate...
‫يا لغباء هذا القرصان‬
You should be good to go.
‫يمكنكم المغادرة الآن‬
The log must have been stored by now.
‫لا بدّ أنّ السجلّ قد اكتمل‬
Is it pointing at the same direction as the map?
‫هل تشير لنفس الاتجاه كما في الخريطة؟‬
Yep.
‫أجل‬
It's pointing at Whisky Peak.
‫إنّها تشير إلى ويسكي بيك‬
See ya, flower guy!
‫إلى اللّقاء يا عجوز الزهرة!‬
Thanks for the log pose!
‫نشكرك على البوصلة المسجّلة!‬
Yeah. Have a safe trip!
‫أجل. أتمنّى لكم رحلة آمنة!‬
See ya, too, whale! I'm leaving now!
‫إلى اللقاء أيها الحوت، سنغادر الآن‬
Full speed ahead...
‫لنذهب صوب ويسكي بيك‬
to Whisky Peak!
‫بأقصى سرعة!‬
– Yeah!
‫أجل!‬
Could they be the pirates we've been waiting for all this time...?
‫أتُراهم القراصنة الذين كنا ننتظرهم طوال الوقت؟‬
That man has a particularly strange air about him...
‫لذلك الرجل حضور عجيب‬
don't you think,
‫ألا تعتقد ذلك...‬
Roger?
‫يا روجر؟‬